DIARRA FALL, PE

NASHVILLE, TN

(615) 638-2772 DIARRA.FALL@OUTLOOK.COM LICENSE NO. 123431 LINKEDIN.COM/IN/DIARRAFALL GITHUB.COM/DIARRA-FALL

Licensed Engineer with 7+ years of experience in traffic engineering, signal design, and structural design. Possess a strong foundation in data analysis/visualization and the desire to apply that to traffic and transportation data.

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL, NASHVILLE, TN

Data Analyst Apprentice, January 2023 - Present

Intensive full-time bootcamp focusing on data analytics fundamentals and problem solving. Used real-world datasets and included projects where findings were presented to stakeholders from the community.

- Analyzed data using Microsoft Excel, including utilizing pivot tables and lookups, and connected to external data sources using the PowerPivot add-on
- Wrangled data and performed exploratory data analysis using Python's pandas library
- Created data visualizations using matplotlib and seaborn
- Retrieved and analyzed data using PostgreSQL
- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with GitHub project boards and issue tracking

KIMLEY-HORN, NASHVILLE, TN

Transportation Engineer, June 2021 – January 2023

- Managed \$400,000+ of projects and tasks, ensuring completion on time and under budget
- Analyzed months of historical traffic data and produced a traffic responsive signal system in East Tennessee
- Led the Concept of Operations and Systems Engineering process for the Nashville Traffic Management Center
- Organized and led workshops, meetings, and designs for the Nashville Traffic Calming Program
- Supervised Traffic E.I. team member, focusing on technical and professional career growth, training and integration, and oversight of work performed
- Performed engineering design services for clients across the state of Tennessee
- Represented Kimley-Horn at National and State technical conferences

TENNESSEE DEPARTMENT OF TRANSPORTATION, NASHVILLE, TN

Transportation Project Specialist (Traffic Operations), August 2018 – June 2021 Safety and Operations

- Performed engineering design and created plans for special projects (a mini roundabout, travel time signs)
- Directed research projects and facilitated quarterly research meetings
- Reviewed manuals, reports, and other documents submitted by consultants
- Engaged in road safety audits with internal divisions and local officials
- Analyzed crash data, composed PM3 report, and reported on congestion and bottlenecks
- Researched and provided responses to traffic operations-related comments from the public

Traffic Signals

- Designed traffic signals in compliance with the MUTCD, Green Book, and TDOT standards
- Created signal plans in MicroStation (placed conduit, signal heads, detection, etc.)
- Coordinated with local officials to ensure that designs suited their needs
- Conducted field reviews of construction plans

Transportation Project Specialist (Structures), January 2017 — August 2018 Graduate Transportation Associate (Structures), January 2016 — January 2017

- Designed prestressed concrete bridges using the LEAP bridge design suite
- Reviewed shop drawings, bridges, culverts, and other structural designs for LRFD compliance
- Communicated plan details to drafters
- Performed grade and quantity checks

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL, NASHVILLE, TN Data Analytics Certification

UNIVERSITY OF TENNESSEE, KNOXVILLE, TN

Master of Science in Civil Engineering (Public Works Concentration)

TENNESSEE STATE UNIVERSITY, NASHVILLE, TN Bachelor of Science in Civil Engineering

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Infrastructure Lead for the Kimley-Horn Nashville Office Women's Leadership Group
- TDOT Graduate Transportation Associate Advisory Board Member created trainings for and provided mentorship to incoming engineers
- Mentor to 3 interns as part of the TDOT Summer Internship Program